{"tossups": [{"question": "Forces from this politician\u2019s country were encircled and forced to surrender during the Christmas Offensive. This politician ordered the bombing of Corfu after their general Enrico Tellini was murdered in Greece. Otto Skorzeny (\"SCORE-zuh-nee\") led an operation to rescue this politician in the Gran Sasso Raid. This politician edited the newspaper Avanti. This politician replaced King Zog with Victor Emmanuel III, and he signed the (*) Lateran Treaty to establish Vatican City. This dictator was replaced by Pietro Badoglio after an Allied invasion of Sicily. This man\u2019s followers were nicknamed the Blackshirts. For 10 points, name this fascist nicknamed \"Il Duce,\" an Italian dictator through WWII.", "answer": "Benito Amilcare Andrea Mussolini", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This composer wrote a song in which the title woman sings \"My peace is gone, my heart is heavy\" and a cycle about a man who drowns himself after seeing his love, a miller\u2019s daughter, seduced by a hunter in green. This composer, who wrote \"Gretchen at the Spinning Wheel\" and the \"Little\" and \"Great\" C Major symphonies, also wrote incidental music for the Helmina von Chezy play (*) Rosamunde. Poems by Wilhelm M\u00fcller inspired his cycle \"Die sch\u00f6ne M\u00fcllerin.\" A B-minor composition by this composer has only two movements and is titled the \"Unfinished\" symphony. For 10 points, name this composer whose works include \"Der Erlkonig\" (\"EARL-kone-iyg\") and \"Ave Maria.\"", "answer": "Franz Peter Schubert", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Different areas on the Ramachandran plot correspond to different outcomes for one phase of this process. According to Anfinsen\u2019s Dogma, this process is entirely dependent upon its input. This process is aided by the hydrophobic effect. A class of heat shock proteins known as chaperonins assist in this process to ensure that it happens properly. The result of this process happening improperly may manifest itself in the form of (*) prions. A certain class of biomolecules acquire their secondary and tertiary structures by undergoing, for 10 points, what process in which proteins take their three-dimensional structure?", "answer": "protein folding [accept folding last line; prompt on partial answers before]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This state\u2019s town of Wallace claims to be the center of the universe since no one can prove it otherwise. Three tourists from Hawaii who died while exploring this state are the namesake of Owyhee (\"ow-WAI-hee\") County. Challis National Forest contains this state\u2019s highest point, Borah Peak, which is found in the Lost River Range. Twin Falls is found near this state's Craters of the Moon National Park. This state features the ski town of (*) Coeur d\u2019Alene (\"kore duh-LANE\"), located in its north, which is in a different time zone from the rest of this state. This state, which lies west of the Bitterroot Range, is home to Lewiston in its panhandle, and a potato museum in its city of Pocatello. For 10 points, name this state with capital Boise (\"BOY-zee\").", "answer": "Idaho", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "The speaker of this poem describes being \"pinned and wriggling on the wall\" by \"the eyes that fix you in a formulated phrase,\" and later says he\"shall wear white flannel trousers, and walk upon the beach.\" That speaker of this poem wonders \"would it have been worth it, after all\" to have \"squeezed the universe into a ball,\" or to say \"I am Lazarus, come from the dead.\" This poem\u2019s speaker claims to have \"measured out [his] life with (*) coffee spoons,\" and this poem ends with \"the mermaids singing, each to each.\" The speaker of this poem wonders \"Do I dare to eat a peach?\" and \"Do I dare disturb the universe?\" For 10 points, name this poem that repeats the lines \"In the room the women come and go / talking of Michelangelo,\" by T. S. Eliot.", "answer": "The Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In this battle, Confederates on Corinth Road hoped to force the Union into a swamp called Owl Creek. The Union was saved from being overwhelmed by a Confederate assault by a barrage of gunboats near Pittsburg Landing during this battle. Before this battle, Lew Wallace sent reinforcements to the wrong location, causing his removal from one general\u2019s army. During this battle, the Union defended a \"sunken road\" known as the (*) \"Hornet\u2019s Nest.\" General Albert Sidney Johnston died during this battle, after which P. G. T. Beauregard took over the Confederate army. For 10 points, name this 1862 victory for Ulysses S. Grant, fought in southwest Tennessee.", "answer": "Battle of Shiloh [accept Battle of Pittsburg Landing before \"Pittsburg Landing\"]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Applying Ampere\u2019s circuital law to the London equations derives an equation used to calculate the London penetration depth of these materials. The inverse of the magnetic flux quantum is a proportionality constant concerning multiple of these materials connected by a weak one of them in a Josephson junction. One theory of the formation of these materials describes them as being caused by the condensation of (*) Cooper pairs. YBCOs are \"high-temperature\" types of these materials. These materials repel internal magnetic fields due to the Meissner effect. For 10 points, name these materials in which current flowing through has no resistance.", "answer": "superconductors [accept type I or type II superconductivity; accept type I or type II superconductors; do NOT accept or prompt on \"conductors\"]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In 2020, this state saw a 109-vote win by Claudia Tenney over Anthony Brindisi. A representative from this state succeeded Liz Cheney (\"chay-nee\") as Chair of the Republican Conference; that representative is Elise Stefanik (\"stuh-fawn-ick\"). This state\u2019s attorney general, Letitia (\"luh-tee-shuh\") James, filed a lawsuit to dissolve the NRA and is leading an investigation over (*) nursing home deaths in this state. A politician from this state proposed a solution to combat automation by implementing Universal Basic Income. Kirsten Gillibrand and the Senate Majority Leader, Chuck Schumer are from this state. Lindsey Boylan and Charlotte Bennet accused this state\u2019s governor of sexual harassment, whose current governor is Kathy Hochul. In August 2021, Andrew Cuomo resigned as governor of, for 10 points, what state with capital Albany?", "answer": "New York", "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events"}, {"question": "After a major event in this book, a man returns with a transformed face and consequently has to wear a veil. God established the Sinaitic Covenant with a certain group in this book, promising them Canaan (\"CANE-nan\"). A ruler in this book ordered all newborn boys to be thrown into a river and led his army to Pi-HaHiroth (\"PIE-HUH-hye-roth\"), where they were drowned in the (*) Red Sea. A series of ten disasters in this book included the Nile River turning into blood and a plague of locusts. In this book, a golden calf cast by Aaron is idolized by the Israelites as Moses receives the Ten Commandments from God. For 10 points, name this second book in the Bible, in which the Israelites leave Egypt.", "answer": "Book of Exodus", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: specific word required. In Death of a Salesman, Willy Loman commits suicide after he sees a vision of his brother Ben telling him that this place \"is dark, but full of diamonds.\" A novel titled for this type of place contains characters like the \"philosophic anarchist\" Dr. Schliemann, the union spy Bush Harper, and Stanislovas, a young boy who is eaten by rats. That novel titled for this type of place ends with the cry \"CHICAGO WILL BE OURS!\" by an orator at a (*) socialist rally, and focuses on the harsh working life of Lithuanian immigrant Jurgis Rudkus. For 10 points, name this type of place that titles an Upton Sinclair novel about the horrors of the meatpacking industry as well as a book by Rudyard Kipling about Shere Khan and Mowgli.", "answer": "Jungle [accept The Jungle; accept The Jungle Book]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A pencil inscription on this painting claims it \"could only have been painted by a madman.\" This painting\u2019s artist detailed its inspiration in a diary entry claiming he felt its title entity \"passing through nature.\" On the day of the 1994 Winter Olympics\u2019 opening, a note reading \"Thanks for the poor (*) security\" was left after this painting\u2019s theft in Oslo. Krakatoa\u2019s eruption may have inspired this painting\u2019s \"blood red\" sky, under which two figures walk on a road behind the distorted central figure. For 10 points, name this painting which shows a man grabbing his face and performing the title action, by Edvard Munch.", "answer": "The Scream [or Skrik; accept Der Schrei der Natur or The Scream of Nature]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "\"Onwards Towards Final Victory\" was a hymn dedicated to a politician from this country. After the murder of two soldiers, Task Force Vierra retaliated against this country in the aptly named Operation Paul Bunyan. After being taken hostage in this country, the crew of the USS Pueblo discreetly gave the middle finger in photographs. This country\u2019s Unit 124 tried to assassinate another country\u2019s president in the (*) Blue House raid. This country\u2019s first leader proposed the \"Juche\" ideology. Alluding to his name, the birthday of one leader of this country is known as the \"Day of the Sun.\" In 2017, this country tested its Hwasong-15 ICBM. For 10 points, name this country led by Kim Jong-un from Pyongyang.", "answer": "North Korea [accept Democratic People\u2019s Republic of Korea or DPRK; do NOT accept or prompt on \"Republic of Korea\"]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "The result of performing this operation can be approximated by using pieces of parabolas. This operation, which can be approximated by Simpson\u2019s rule, is 0 when applied to odd functions over the interval [-a,a]. The limit as n approaches infinity of the sum [f of x sub i] times delta x gives an approximation for this value which gets closer to the actual value as n, or the number of (*) rectangles between a function\u2019s graph and the x-axis approaches infinity. Taking a function\u2019s antiderivative and plugging in the \"limits\" for performing this action yields an exact value for, for 10 points, what calculus operation used to find the area under a curve?", "answer": "Definite Integral [accept word forms like integration]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In this show, a Russian code beginning \"The week is long. The silver cat feeds when blue meets yellow in the west\" is shown by the Scoops Ahoy employee Robin to refer to Starcourt Mall shops. One protagonist\u2019s claim that \"he likes it cold\" leads a group of characters in this show to overheat him, ending his possession by a \"mind flayer.\" In this show\u2019s first season, Barb goes missing at a pool party. A mother in this show tries to use (*) Christmas lights to communicate with her son, who is trapped by a demogorgon in the Upside Down. The telekinetic Eleven helps middle school Dungeons and Dragons players search for Will Byers in this show\u2019s first season. For 10 points, name this supernatural mystery Netflix show set in the 1980s.", "answer": "Stranger Things", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "One character created by this author has parents who were once part of the Takashima commune and writes the novel Air Chrysalis. Another of this author\u2019s characters climbs out of a taxi and down an emergency escape after hearing Janacek\u2019s (\"YAH-nah-check\u2019s\") Sinfonietta. This author created Tengo and Aomame (\"ow-mah-may\") in a novel that ends with them leaving a world with two moons. This author also created a character traumatized by his service in Manchukuo, Lieutenant (*) Mamiya, and the clairvoyant Malta Kano in a novel that opens with the section \"The Thieving Magpie.\" In that novel, Toru Okada is instructed to find a missing cat by his wife Kumiko. For 10 points, name this Japanese author of 1Q84 and The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle.", "answer": "Haruki Murakami", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A researcher studying this language observed that women used both its prestige and innovative variants more than men. That researcher, who noted the \"gender paradox,\" also studied the use of rhoticity in department store clerks of differing social classes using this language. That researcher was William Labov. This language\u2019s Northern Cities Vowel Shift changed pronunciations established by the earlier Great (*) Vowel Shift. This language\u2019s \"Old\" form changed after a Norman conquest in 1066. For 10 points, name this Germanic language, whose \"vernacular\" is used by African Americans, and is the language spoken in the US.", "answer": "English", "subcategory": "Social Science", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "The Lerma River, which ends in Lake Chapala, flows through this country. In this country, a building owned by its national petrol company exploded in its city of Reynosa. It's not Bolivia, but the Peninsular Ranges in this country cross the city of La Paz. People cliff dive at La Quebrada in a city on this country\u2019s western coast, (*) Acapulco. This country's city of Ciudad Ju\u00e1rez is located on the Rio Grande River, which forms its northern border. This country owns the majority of the Yucatan peninsula on which its city of Canc\u00fan lies. Quintana Roo and Chihuahua are states of, for 10 points, what country, the second most populous in North America, located south of the USA?", "answer": "Mexico [accept United Mexican States or Estados Unidos Mexicanos]", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "One idea from this country was originated by the victors of the Battle of Muye. The Annals (\"ANNE-ulz\") were a piece of literature from this country titled for its Spring and Autumn Period, which also saw the creation of the \"Hundred Schools of Thought.\" That period was followed by this country\u2019s (*) Warring States Period. A text from this country advises readers to \"know your enemy and know yourself.\" This country\u2019s rulers are believed to hold the Mandate of Heaven, and this country originated Sun Tzu\u2019s The Art of War. For 10 points, name this country divided into dynasties such as the Shang, Zhou (\"JOE\"), and Qin (\"CHIN\").", "answer": "China [or Zhongguo]", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This element's spin-flip transitions cause its namesake 21 cm line. This element's emission spectrum includes the Lyman series. This is the only neutral element for which Schrodinger\u2019s equation can be solved perfectly. Gases of this element and nitrogen react with an iron catalyst in the (*) Haber-Bosch process. The negative logarithm of the concentration of this element\u2019s ion in a solution is used to describe its acidity. A namesake type of bonding occurs between this element and others, such as oxygen or fluorine. An isotope of this element makes up a substance often used in nuclear reactors, \"heavy water.\" Deuterium and tritium are isotopes of, for 10 points, what lightest element symbolized H?", "answer": "hydrogen [accept H before mention]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This poet included \"The City That Does Not Sleep\" in their collection Poet in New York. In one poem, this poet describes a girl \"with eyes of cold silver\" as well as \"the ship out to sea / and the horse on the mountain.\" Allen Ginsberg wonders what this non-Whitman poet is doing \"down by the watermelons\" in \"A Supermarket in California.\" Another poem by this author of \"Romance Son\u00e1mbulo\" repeats the line \"I will not see it\" in its section \"The Spilled (*) Blood.\" An event that occured \"at five in the afternoon\" is the main subject of this poet\u2019s \"Lament for the Death of a Bullfighter.\" For 10 points, what author included \"Blood Wedding\" as part of his \"Rural Trilogy?\"", "answer": "Federico Garcia Lorca", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": []}